你有没有意识到再过4个星期  我们就要结婚了
Do you realize that four weeks from today we're getting married?
4个星期  宝贝  4个星期
Four weeks, baby. Four weeks!
你有没有意识到你的嗓门越来越大了
You realize you get louder each week?
还有这么多事要做  你写好你的婚礼誓词了吗
There's still so much to do! Have you written your vows yet?
我想我会去买 "派特  我要买婚礼誓词"
I figured I'd just buy those. "Pat, I'd like to buy a vow." Ha, ha.
亲爱的  你知道讲到婚礼  我是没有幽默感的
Sweetie, you know I've no sense of humor when it comes to the wedding.
对  你写了你的了吗  还没有  但我知道我要说什么
Right. So uh, have you written yours yet? No, but I know exactly what I'm gonna say.
你会不会刚好知道  我要说什么呢
Do you happen to know what I'm gonna say?
现在写  没有那么困难
Let's just do it right now. Okay? It won't be hard.
说你心里想的
Just say what's in your heart.
看她写得多快  她一定爱我比我爱她更多
Look at her go. She must love me more than I love her!
我是怎么啦  噢  不要开始这么想
What's wrong with me? Ooh, don't open that door.
老友记  第七季  第21集  婚誓
Friends  S07E021  The One With The Vows
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
"摩妮卡  没有字"
Phew. "Monica, there are no words--"
没有字  这不应该这么难
There are no words! This shouldn't be this hard!
这你做过了  你的婚礼誓词里要说什么
All right, uh...Uh-Oh! You've done this before. What did you say in your vows?
对卡萝  我承诺过对她至死不渝
Well with Carol, I promised never to love another woman until the day I die.
她却没有这样保证过
She made no such promise.
我真悲哀  摩妮卡知道要说什么  你没看到她下笔如飞的样子
I'm so pathetic! Monica knows what she wants to say! you should have seen her. Writing, writing, writing!
摩妮卡  什么  紧急大事
Monica what? What?! What's the emergency?
帮我忙  我一定要写婚礼誓词  可是我只写了这些
You have to help me I'm supposed to be writing my vows and all I have is this.
嗯  我喜欢你穿婚纱的画
Well, I like the pretty little drawing of you in the wedding dress.
谢谢  只是除了你的胸部看起来有一点小外
Thank you. Yeah, except your breasts look small.
那是我的眼睛
Those are my eyes!
这才是我的胸部  是嘛  好吧
Those are my breasts. Oh, yeah.
你何不从简单的开始
Well, why don't you just start with something simple?
像是
Like, urn:
"摩妮卡  我一遇到你就爱上了你"
"Monica, from the moment I met you I knew I loved you."
我做不到
Yeah, I' m not sure I can't do that.
各位  这是钱德
Everyone, this is Chandler.
我是罗斯的小妹
Hi, I'm Ross' little sister.
是噢
0Kay.
好吧  好吧  也许你这么起头好了
Okay, okay. Um, maybe you could start with:
"钱德  即使在我们还是朋友时
"Chandler, even though we were friends...
我内心就想进一步发展"
...there was a part of me that always knew I wanted more."
好吧  假如人类发生了一场核子浩劫  我是地球上最后一个男人
All right, there's a nuclear holocaust. I'm the last man on Earth.
你会和我约会吗
Would you go outwith me?
婚礼誓词里可以说谎吗
Ooh! Are we allowed to lie in the vows?
也许那时不要谈你的感情   就说些
Well maybe you don't talk about those feelings back then. Maybe you just say something about y'know ...
他教会你的事  像是
...all the things he's taught you, like--
或是你教会他的事
Or all the things you taught him.
大家都知道基本的性感带  有1  2  3
Everybody knows the basic erogenous zones. One, two, three...
4  5  6才 7
...four, five, six and seven.
有7个
There are seven?
那个也算吗  那个还蛮重要的
That's one? Heh, heh. It's kind of an important one.
你看嘛  我是倒着看的
Oh, y'know-y'know what,I was looking at it upside down.
有时候这样也有帮助的
Ha. You know, sometimes that helps.
好  现在  由1开始
Okay, start out with a little one...
一个2  一个123
...a two, a one-two-three...
一个3  一个5
...a three, a five...
一个4  一个32
...a four, a three-two...
2  一个246
...two, a two-four-six.
246  4  2
Two-four-six, four, two...
2  47
...two, four-seven...
57  67
...five-seven, six-seven...
7  7
. . seven, seven...
7   7   7
. . seven, seven, seven...
"seven!
Seven.
我知道了  这样如何
Oh! I got it. How about saying something like:
"摩妮卡  回忆起我们在一起的时光"
"Monica, when I look back over our time together..."
然后呢  不能全部都要我说吧
Yeah? I can't do all of it.
回忆你们在一起的时光
Look back over your time together.
看  双胞胎
Oh, look, twins!
不公平  我连一个都没有  为什么他们有两个
No fair! I don't even have one, how come they get two?
你会有个的  是啊  什么时候
You'll get one. Yeah, when?
这样吧  我告诉你
All right, I'll tell you what.
等40岁的时候  如果我们都还没结婚
When we're 40, if neither of us are married...
我们俩来生个如何  我为什么会40岁还没结婚
...what do you say you and I get together and have one? Why wouldn't I be married when I'm 40?
不  不  我只是说"假设"
Oh, no, no, no. I just meant hypothetically.
好  我们来假设  我为什么会40岁还没结婚
Ok, Hypothetically, why won't I be married when I'm 40?
不  不  不
No, no. no.
怎么了  我是真有什么不能结婚的地方吗
What is it? ls there something fundamentally unmarriable about me?
怎么样
Uh-Uh--Well?
我的老天  这个降落伞是一个背包
Dear God, this parachute is a knapsack!
今天我要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
他知道我在这儿吗
Do you think he knew I was here?
算你尽力了
Nice try.
等一下  等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
摩妮卡
Look, Monica-Ah!
没有用的  我保证这有用
Look! This is not gonna work. I bet this'll work.
你真棒  我爱你
You are so great! I love you.
什么
What?
没事  我说  你真棒  然后就没说话了
Nothing! I said, I said you're so great, and then I just, I just stopped talking.
你说你爱我  我不敢相信  不  我没有
You said you love me! I can't believe this! No, I didn't.
有  你有  没有  我没有
Yes, you did. No, I didn't!
你爱我  不  我不爱
You love me! No, I don't!
停  停  停  停
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
我在想  如果我在这里  打开行李呢
You know, I was thinking, what if I, uh, unpack here?
你的东西都会在这里
Then all your stuff would be here.
那
Well...
如果我的东西都在这里呢
What if all my stuff was here?
那你会一直来回跑来跑去
Then you'd be going back and forth all the time.
干嘛要那样呢
Doesn't make any sense.
好
0Kay.
那如果我们是住在一起  你明白我在说什么嘛
What if we live together, and you understand what I'm saying?
你希望这是一个惊喜
You wanted it to be a surprise.
我的天
Oh, my God!
钱德
Chandler...
我这一生
...in all my life...
从没想过我会这么幸运
...I never thought I'd be so lucky...
能爱上我最好的
...as to fall in love with my best--
我最好的  女生不这么做是有原因的
My best-There's a reason why girls don't do this!
好  好  我来
Okay, okay, okay! I'll do it.
我以为
I thought--
我做得到
I can do this.
我以为
I thought...
我说什么  和在哪里说很重要
...that it mattered what I said or where I said it.
但我发现唯一重要的是你
Then I realized the only thing that matters is that you--
你让我比我能想像的更快乐
You make me happier than I ever thought I could be.
如果你愿意
And if you let me...
我要用这一生  来让你有同样的感觉
...I'll spend the rest of my life trying to make you feel the same way.
摩妮卡
Monica?
嫁给我好吗
Will you marry me?
好
Yes.
我们可以进来了吗  我们快要憋死了
Can we come in? We're dying out here!
进来  进来
Come in! Come in!
我们订婚了    好啊
We're engaged! Yes!
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
嗨  你们在干嘛
Hi. What have you guys been up to?
帮钱德写他的婚礼誓词  他把我们赶出来了
Oh, we were helping Chandler write his vows. but he kicked us out
因为乔伊老是想一些不合时宜的点子
because Joey kept making inappropriate suggestions.
"摩妮卡  我爱你的美臀"  这有什么不得体
How is "Monica, I love your sweet ass" inappropriate?
摩妮卡写得怎么样了
How's Monica coming along with her vows?
这样说吧  幸好她有一个美臀  因为她不太擅长写作
Well let's just say its she's lucky she's got a sweet ass. She's not so good at writing.
真不敢相信再过4个星期  他们就要结婚了
I can't believe in four weeks they're gonna be married!
希望他们能白头到老
Let's just hope it works.
10个里面有9个以离婚收场
Y"know nine out of 1O marriages end in divorce.
菲比  没有的事
Phoebe that's not true.
是啊  你说的对  你太太好吗
Yeah, you're right. How's the missus?
真不敢相信
I can't believe...
他们在一起3年了  那么久了
...they've been together 3 years. Has it been that long?!
感觉没那么久  因为他们瞒了我们很久
Believe me, it seems like less because they hid it from us for so long.
是我  进来了
Hey, it's me. Coming in.
我今天辛苦了一整天
I've had a very long, hard day.
我要去买炸鸡  你要不要  不  谢了  不要炸鸡  再见
Ahh, I'm gonna go get some chicken. Want some? Ahh, no thanks. No chicken, bye-bye then.
你还好吧  抱歉
Are you okay? I'm so sorry.
他不肯离开  一直问我要不要炸鸡
He wouldn't leave. He kept asking if I wanted chicken.
炸鸡
Chicken?
我可以来点炸鸡
I could eat some chicken.
乔伊
Hey, Joe!
我想要三块鸡肉  包心菜沙拉  豆子  还有可乐
Can I get a, uh, three-piece, some cole slaw, some beans, and a Coke—
健怡可乐
Diet Coke.
不知道他们为什么不直接告诉我们  对啊  好像我们不会认同似的
I don't know why they didn't just tell us. I know, I mean it's not like we weren't cool about it.
你  还有你
You? And you?
对  但你不能说  没有人知道
Yes, but you cannot tell anyone! No one knows.
怎么会  什么时候
How? When?
在伦敦发生的  在伦敦啊
It happened in London. In London?
我们没告诉任何人  因为我们不希望小事变大
The reason we didn't tell anyone was because we didn't want to make a big deal out of it.
可是这是大事
But it is a big deal!
我一定要告诉别人  不  不要
I have to tell someone. No-no-no-no-no!
不行  拜托  拜托
You can't. Please! Please?!
我们还不想告诉他们  答应我你不会说
We just don't want to deal with telling everyone, okay? Just promise you won't tell.
好的
All right!
我都等不及想和你在一起
I can't wait to be with you!
我去告诉瑞秋  我要洗几个小时的衣服
I'll just tell Rachel I'm gonna be doing laundry for a couple of hours.
洗衣服  那是我的新昵称吗
Laundry, huh? Is that my new nickname?
你知道你的昵称是什么  大
You know what your nickname, Mr. Big--
看  是摩妮卡和钱德  嘿  嘿  你们两个  嘿
Oh, look, there's Monica and Chandler. Hey! Hey, you guys! Hey!
钱德和摩妮卡
Chandler and Monica!
我的天
Oh, my God!
钱德和摩妮卡  我的天
Aah! Chandler and Monica! Oh, my God!
我的眼睛  我的眼睛  菲比  菲比
Oh, my eyes! My eyes! Phoebe! Phoebe!
没事的  没事的  不  他们在亲热
It's okay! It's okay! No! They're doing it!
我知道  我知道
I know! I know!
你知道  对  我知道
You know? Yes! I know!
乔伊也知道  但罗斯不知道  你就不要再尖叫了
And Joey knows! but Ross doesn't know so you have to stop screaming!
嗨  怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
什么  怎么了
What? What?
没什么  老天  我们就是太兴奋  想到你会搬到这儿
Nothing! Oh God, we're just so excited that you want to get this apartment!
事实上  这里看起来很不错  看来很不错
Actually, it looks really good. It looks pretty good!
过来  这里来
Get in here! Come on!
现在他们知道你知道  但他们不知道瑞秋知道
Okay, so now they know that you know and they don't know that Rachel knows?
对  但你知道吗  谁知道什么并不重要
Yes, but y'know what? it doesn't matter who knows what.
现在有足够的人知道  就可以告诉他们我们知道了
Now, enough of us know that we can just tell them that we know.
谎言  秘密终于可以结束了
Then all the lying and the secrets would finally be over!
或者我们不要告诉他们我们知道  我们就可以找点小乐子
Or, we can not tell them we know and have a little fun of our own.
好  如果想赶上电影的话  我们该走了
All right honey, We better go if we're gonna catch that movie.
再见  再见
Bye. Bye.
再见  钱德  我已经开始想你了
Bye, Chandler. I miss you already.
你看到了吗  她的那些勾引了吗
Okay, did you see that?! With the inappropriate pinching?
我看到了
Actually, I did.
现在你相信她被我吸引了吧
So now do you believe that she's attracted to me?
我的天  我的天  她知道我们的事
Oh, my God! My God, she knows about us!
菲比知道我们的事  我没有告诉她们
Phoebe knows about us! Well I didn't tell them.
她们  她们是谁
Them? Who's them?
菲比和乔伊
Uh, Phoebe and Joey.
乔伊
Joey!
还有瑞秋
And Rachel.
我本来要告诉你们的  可是她们要我保证不说
I would've told you but they made me promise not to tell.
她们以为她们很厉害  这样耍我们
Oh man, they think they are so slick, messing with us!
可是  她们不知道  我们知道她们知道
But see they don't know that we know that they know.
所以  对
So... Ah, yes!
耍人的要变成被耍的了
Ahh yes, the messers become the mes-sees!
我的天  他要我过去  摸他的二头肌还有别的啥的
My God, he wants me to come over and feel his biceps and more!
你开玩笑吧  没有
Are you kidding? No.
我不相信  他会对摩妮卡这样
I can't believe he'd do that to Mo--
乔伊  他们知道我们知道了吗
Joey? Do they know that we know?
不知道  乔伊
No. Joey!
他们知道你们知道  我就知道
They know you know. Ugh! I knew it!
不能相信这两个人
Oh I cannot believe those two!
他们以为可以耍我们  他们想要耍我们
God, they thought that they could mess with us? They're trying to mess with us?!
他们不知道我们知道  他们知道我们知道
They don't know that we know they know we know.
乔伊  你什么也不能说
Joey, you can't say anything.
就算我想说  也不知道要怎么说
I couldn't even if I wanted too.
这完全失控了
Listen, this is totally getting out of hand.
她要我替她抹乳液  她在唬你
Okay? She wants me to put lotion on her! She's bluffing!
她没有退缩  她还这样
Look, she's not backing down. She went like this.
他没有退缩  他去拿乳液了
He's not backing down. He went to get lotion.
天啊  你们还没玩完吗
Oh, man. Aren't you guys done yet?
乔伊  菲比早点搞定钱德  这事就会早一点公开  早点结束
Joey look, just look at it this way, the sooner Phoebe breaks Chandler the sooner this is all over and out in the open.
我喜欢  好
Ooh, I like that. Okay.
对了  给他看你的胸罩  他最怕胸罩了  他不会解胸罩
Okay, show him your bra. He's afraid of bras. Can't work them.
哇  你是怎么没扯掉任何扣子
Wow! You didn't rip off any buttons.
也不是第一次了
It's not my first time.
去到外面  继续勾引她  直到她崩溃为止
You go back out there and you seduce her until she cracks.
好  给我一秒钟
Okay, give me a second.
你在打扫这里  当然
Did you clean up in here? Of course.
你要走了
Oh, you're, uh, going?
除非你一起来  爱人
Um, not without you, lover.
这是我的胸罩
So, this is my bra.
非常非常的好看
It's very, very nice.
过来
Well, come here.
我非常开心  我们可以一起做爱
I'm very happy we're gonna have all the sex.
你会的  我身体很柔软的
You should be. Heh. I'm very bendy.
我现在要吻你了  如果我没先吻你的话
I'm gonna kiss you now. Not if I kiss you first.
我想我们除了接吻  没有别的事可做了
Well, I guess there's nothing left for us to do but-but kiss.
来了
Here it comes.
我们的初吻
Our first kiss.
好  好  好  你赢了 哈
Okay, okay, okay, fine, you win! You win!! Ha!
我不能和你上床  为什么不能
I can't have sex  with ya! And why not?!
因为我爱摩妮卡  你什么
Because I'm in love with Monica!! You're what?
爱她  对  我爱她  我爱她
Love her! That's right, I love her! I love her!
我爱你  摩妮卡
I love you, Monica.
我也爱你  钱德
I love you too, Chandler.
我以为你们两个只是上床  我不知道你们恋爱了
I thought you guys were doing it, I didn't know you were in love.
就是这样  结束了  大家都知道了
That's it, it's over. Everybody knows.
其实  罗斯还不知道  请大家还不要告诉他
Well actually, Ross doesn't. Yes, and we'd appreciate it if no one told him yet.
不  不
No. No! Wh
你在干什么
What are you doing?
放开我妹
Get off my sister!
朋友要结婚了  很多事会改变的
Y'know, you're friends getting married, it's gotta change things.
你觉得真的会不一样吗
You really think it'll be that different?
怎么能不变呢  他们很快就会有小孩
How can it not be? I mean pretty soon they're gonna have kids...
会和其他有孩子的夫妇在一起
...and then they're just gonna be hanging out with other couples who have kids.
也许他们会搬离城市
And then maybe they're gonna have to leave the city...
到某个靠近富豪车商的地方
...to be near a Volvo dealership.
事情会变的
Well, things change.
我不要他们搬到  卖富豪车的地方
I don't want them to move to a Volvo dealership.
乔伊  不会怎么样的
It'll be okay, Joe. Heh.
抱歉  我只是  我希望能像以前一样
Sorry. I just-I like things the way they are.
这个光着身子的小孩是谁
Who's this little naked guy?
这个光着身子的小孩是我
Uh, that naked guy would be me.
你看这小东西
Ha, aw, look at the little thing. Ha-ha-ha.
是啊
Yes.
是的  好  那是我的小鸡鸡  我们能不能成熟点嘛
Yes, fine, that is my penis. Can we be grownups now?
这些是谁  问倒我了
Who are those people? Got me.
那中间的是奶奶
Oh, that's Nana right there in the middle.
我看看
Wow. Let's see.
"我和爪哇咖啡店里的那一群"
"Me and the gang at Java Joe's."
摩妮卡  你长得很像你祖母  那时她几岁
Wow. Monica, you look just like your grandma. How old was she?
我看看  1939
Let's see, 1939.
对  24  25岁
Yeah, uh, 24, 25.
看起来很快乐的一群
Huh. Looks like a fun gang.
看  看  看  我找到摩妮卡光着身子的
Ooh! Look, look, look! I got Monica naked.
我看
Let me see.
不  这还是我
No, that would be me again.
嘿  大伙儿
Hey, you guys.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
你们在做什么  我们刚刚提到
What's going on? Well, we were just talking about...
你们要结婚了  是大喜事啊
...you guys getting married and how great it is.
对  如果你们真的想要  可以买一台沃尔沃
Yeah, you can get a Volvo. If that's what you really want.
你们真好
Oh that's so sweet. Hmm.
我们都写完婚礼誓词了  我们可以看吗
So, we both finished our vows. Can we read them?
当然可以  只要我没听到钱德的  他没听到我的就好
Yeah, I don't hear Chandler's and he doesn't hear mine.
好  好
Okay. Okay.
噢  那段写的太美了
Oh, that's beautiful.
很搞笑呀   不错
Funny one! That's good!
摩妮卡  你嫁给我好吗
Monica,  will-will you marry me?
什么  我不懂
Ha-ha-ha. What? I don't get it.
是哟
Oh, yeah!
这太搞笑了  钱德
Oh man, this is hilarious! Chandler!
甜心  别担心  我们会让你的更搞笑的
Don't worry, we'll make yours funnier.
好了  你们觉得如何
Okay, what do you guys think?
老兄  我从没见过这样的爱
Dude... I have never known love like this.
你真的喜欢  老兄
You really like it? Dude!
你怎么写出来的
How did you write this?
我偷了摩妮卡的  然后改掉名字
I stole Monica's and changed the name. Shh.
你不能这么做  如果他先讲的话就可以
You can't do that! If he goes first he can!